Guide to the McGraw family papers, 1854-1956.
McGraw family papers, 1854-1956.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
McGraw family papers, 1854-1956.
2355
.5 cubic ft; 4 folders.
Correspondence, financial and legal documents, diaries, photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Business and family correspondence, relating to lumbering interests near Canadea, New York; McGraw family genealogy; diaries and accounts of travels in France, Italy, Germany, Russia, and Egypt; Jennie McGraw Fiske diaries refer to travels in England and on the Continent, and to Chicago, Detroit, Philadelphia, and New York. Other subjects include Cornell University faculty members, the settlement of the estate of John McGraw, and a memorial to McGraw by the Cornell University Board of Trustees. Major correspondents and persons figuring prominently in the collection include Douglass Boardman, J. W. Dwight, Willard Fiske, Mary Celestia McGraw, John Ellis Southworth, and Anna Gauntlett Whitcomb.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Business and family correspondence, relating to lumbering interests near Canadea, New York; McGraw family genealogy; diaries and accounts of travels in France, Italy, Germany, Russia, and Egypt; Jennie McGraw Fiske diaries refer to travels in England and on the Continent, and to Chicago, Detroit, Philadelphia, and New York. Other subjects include Cornell University faculty members, the settlement of the estate of John McGraw, and a memorial to McGraw by the Cornell University Board of Trustees. Major correspondents and persons figuring prominently in the collection include Douglass Boardman, J. W. Dwight, Willard Fiske, Mary Celestia McGraw, John Ellis Southworth, and Anna Gauntlett Whitcomb.
Also, a Jennie McGraw letter to her uncle, Thomas McGraw, describing the impact of the Civil War on Detroit, and mentioning mutual acquaintances involved in the struggle. John McGraw papers refer to Cornell University lands, lands held by the H. W. Sage and Company, and his own personal matters; includes Henry Williams Sage correspondence. McGraw's involvement in the lumber industry is documented by correspondence with William E. Taylor regarding lumber prices in Ontario, Canada, and by exchanges with mill operators and lumbering concerns in Ontario, Wisconsin, and Minnesota.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McGraw family.; Boardman, Douglass, 1822-1891.; Dwight, J. W.; Fiske, Jennie McGraw, 1840-1881.; Fiske, Willard, 1831-1904.; McGraw, John.; McGraw, Mary Celestia.; Sage, Henry W.(Henry Williams), 1814-1897.; Southworth, John Ellis.; Taylor, William E.; Whitcomb, Anna Gauntlett.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University.Board of Trustees.; H. W. Sage and Company.; W.J. Young and Company.
Subjects:
Lumber trade--Wisconsin.; Lumber trade--Minnesota.; Lumber trade--Canada--Ontario.; Lumber trade--New York (State)--Canadea.; Mills and mill-work--Canada--Ontario.; Mills and mill-work--Wisconsin.; Mills and mill-work--Minnesota.; Genealogy--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Family--New York (State)--Ithaca
Places:
France--Description and travel.; Italy--Description and travel.; Germany--Description and travel.; Russia--Description and travel.; Egypt--Description and travel.; England--Description and travel.; Chicago (Ill.)--Description and travel.; Detroit (Mich.)--Description and travel.; Philadelphia (Pa.)--Description and travel.; New York (N.Y.)--Description and travel.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Box: 1
Series II. Diaries
Box: 1
Series III. Financial and Legal Documents
Box: 1
Series IV. W.J. Young and Company
Box: 1
Series V. Miscellaneous
Box: 1
Series VI. Photographs
Box: 1
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - General, 1846-1858 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General, 1860-1869 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jennie McGraw Letter to Thomas McGraw, October 19, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General, 1873-June 1878 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General, July-September 1878 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General, October 1878 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General, November-December1878 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General, 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General, January -July 1881 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - General, 1887-1890 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - General, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - McGraw Genealogy, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - McGraw Genealogy, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series II. Diaries
  - Jennie McGraw Diary, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Jennie McGraw Diary, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series III. Financial and Legal Documents
  - Documents, 1847-1861 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Documents, 1865-1868 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Documents, 1869-1871 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Documents, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Documents, 1874-1875 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Documents, 1876-1877 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Documents, January-June 1878 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Documents, July-October 1878 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Documents, November-December 1878 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Documents, January-March 1879 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Documents, April 1879 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Documents, May 1879 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Documents, June-December 1879 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Documents, 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series IV. W.J. Young and Company
  - Documents, 1876-1877 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Documents, January-April 1878 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Documents, May-July 1878 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Documents, August-December 1878 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Documents, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Documents, April-August 1880 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Documents, September-December 1880 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Documents, January-June 1881 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Documents, July-December 1881 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Documents, January-March 1882 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Documents, April-June 1882 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Documents, July-November 1882 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Series V. Miscellaneous
  - Clippings regarding death of Mary Cornell, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Four land grants from General Land Office of the United States, May 21, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1874-1941 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Miscellaneous items, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Series VI. Photographs
  - Painted portrait of Jennie McGraw Fiske (Box M.S. box, Folder 1)
    Formerly on display in the A.D. White library
  - Daguerreotype of Jennie McGraw, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - John McGraw?, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Ezra Cornell, September 1862 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jennie McGraw Fiske about 38 years of age, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - McGraw-Fiske Mansion (3 images), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - McGraw-Fiske Mansion (3 images), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - McGraw-Fiske Mansion (3 images), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - McGraw-Fiske Mansion (3 images), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jane McGraw, John's second wife (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - John McGraw, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (4 images), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Steel Plate: John McGraw, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)